A Finding Aid to the Tomás Ybarra-Frausto Research Material on Chicano Art, 1965-2004, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ybartoma
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1965-1997; Series 1
  - L.A. Iluminado: Eight Los Angeles Photographers, Exhibition, Otis/Parsons Gallery, Otis/Parsons School of Art and Design (see also: Aguilar, Laura; Gamboa, Harry Jr.; Photography; Romero, Frank), 1991; (catalog) (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - L.A. L.A., Exhibition, United Latinos for the Arts of Los Angeles, Pico House, Los Angeles, California (see also: Almaraz, Carlos; Botello, David; García, Margaret; Healy, Wayne; Herrón, Willie; Valadez, John; Valdez, Patssi), 1989; (exhibition announcement; catalog) (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Latin America, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    (journal, Border/Lines: Canada's Magazine of Cultural Studies, issue no. 27, special issue on Latin America)
  - Latin America Art Association for San Antonio (ALAA; see also: Quirarte, Jacinto), 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    (incomplete handbook with memo to ALAA members from Jacinto Quirarte, President)
  - Latin American Literature, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    (Stanford Dept. of Spanish and Portuguese Ph.D. examination reading list)
  - The Latin American Spirit: Art and Artists in the U.S., 1920-1970, Exhibition, Bronx Museum of Art, New York, 1988; (exhibition announcement; press release) (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Latina/Latino Art Auction and Symposia, Hispanic Research Center, Arizona State University, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    (information packet with symposium session schedule where TYF made a presentation; agenda and logistics; program overview)
  - Latino Collaborative, Organization, New York (see also: Noriega, Chon; Valadez, John), 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    (workshop announcement; membership information; newsletter: Mar/Apr-July/Aug. 1990, Mar/Apr 1991, May/Jun 1992, Jan/Feb 1993-May/Jun 1993, Jan/Feb 1994)
  - Latino Cultural Center (see also: Muñoz, Celia), 2002-2003, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    (clipping; floor plan; resume of Tomas Bustos, sculptor; exhibition announcement; grand opening booklet)
  - Latino Designers, undated; (directory) (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Latino Media Arts: Theory and Culture, Conference, Whitney Museum of American Art, New York, undated, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    (schedule; TYF's notes)
  - Latino Museum of History, Art and Culture, Los Angeles, California (see also: An American Leader - Cesar Chavez; Los Four; Goldman, Shifra), 1996, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    (information packets with organization's history, mission, exhibit information, clippings, letters of support to Denise Lugo, executive director, Latino Museum; exhibition announcements; invitation; fact sheet; article by Shifra Goldman; slides; press release)
  - Latino Interest Network (LIN), Organization, Fort Lauderdale, Florida, 1994; (meeting minutes 02/12/1994) (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Latino National Political Survey, Stanford University, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    (letter to Dr. Luis Fraga, Director Stanford Center for Chicano Research, Stanford/University, from Chris Garcia and other investigators of the Latino National Political Survey - LNPS, 02/18/1994, photocopy, with enclosed comments on Fraga's report on LNPS; monograph, Still Looking for America: Beyond the Latino National Political Survey, Public Outreach Project, Stanford Center for Chicano Research, Stanford, California, 1994)
  - Latino Population, 1970, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    (Monograph, We The Mexican Americans/Nosotros Los México Americanos, United States Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census, 1970; clipping)
  - Latino Redux, Exhibition, 2000; (clipping) (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Latinos in Museums, Conference, Inter-University Project, University of Arizona, 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    (agendas; clipping; proposal; program abstract; Latino Caucus discussion summary; meeting minutes and summaries; monograph, "El Orgullo de Ser: Latino Public History: Applied History Programs, Exhibitions and Museums" by Antonio Rios-Bustamantel; TYF's notes)
  - Lecture Materials, 1970-1980, undated (Box 15)
    - Lecture, undated; (clippings) (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Chicanismo, 1970, undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
      (typescript of lecture, "Chicanismo" given by Thomas M. Martinez at the Chicano Studies Institutes, Summer, 1970; 1 p. of TYF's notes on "Elementos del Barroco en la psicologia del Chicano")
    - Notes, 1976-1980 (Box 15, Folder 27)
      (notes on notecards and on paper on various aspects and periods of arte chicano); bibliographic notes; letter to TYF from Barbara Pascal, undated; letter to TYF from Matt S. Meier and Francisco Jiménez, Dept. of Modern Languages, University of Santa Clara, 10/15/1980, asking TYF to do a lecture)
  - León-Portilla, Miguel, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
    (photocopy of essay, "The Norteño Variety of Mexican Culture: An Ethnohistorical Approach" by León-Portilla)
  - Lerma, José Ramon, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    (exhibition announcement addressed and signed by Lerma)
  - Lettuce Boycott (see also: Huerta, Dolores), 1966-1995 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    (booklet; book, Don Sotaco: Cartoons from the Delano Strike, Farm Workers Press, Inc., Delano, California, 1966; invitation to Dolores Huerta's 65th birthday celebration)
  - Licon, Carlos, Painter (1929-1982; see also: La Raza/Galería Posada), 1985-1989 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    (catalogs; exhibition announcement)
  - Lockpez, Inverna (see: International Arts Relations, Inc.) (Box 15)
  - Lomas-Garza, Carmen, (6 folders; see also: CARA; Garcia, Rupert; Gronk; Box 30; OV 32) (Box 15, Folder 32-37)
    (exhibition announcements; exhibition brochures; catalogs; resume; sales receipt; book by Lomas Garza, Papel Picado: Paper Cutout Techniques, Xicanindio Arts Coalition, Mesa, Arizona, 1984; TYF's notes on Lomas Garza; clippings; oversize materials; slides; note to TYF from Lomas Garza, undated; note to TYF and Dudley, from Lomas Garza, undated; typescript of essay on Lomas Garza by TYF, from the catalog, Carmen Lomas Garza: Lo Real Maravilloso: the Marvelous/The Real, The Mexican Museum, San Francisco, 1988; catalog, Mano a Mano: Abstraction/Figuration: 16 Mexican-American & Latin-American Painters from the San Francisco Bay Area, The Art Museum of Santa Cruz County and University of California Santa Cruz, 1988; Festival Internaxional de la Raza, "Los Artistas Chicanos del Valle de Tejas: Narradores de Mitos Y Tradiciones," 1991; Handwritten transcript of interview with Lomas Garza by TYF; polaroid photographs of Lomas Garza; memo to Dudley and TYF from Vincente M. Martinez, Acting Chief Curator Millicent Rogers Museum, 04/03/1995, re. invitations to exhibition opening and loan of piece)
  - López, Alma (see also: Museum of International Folk Art), 1999-2004 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    (postcard to TYF from López, 1/30/01; exhibition announcements; series of emails re. López' "Our Lady" in the Cyber Arte exhibition, Museum of International Folk Art, Sante Fe, New Mexico, 2001; invitation; clippings; writings by López; resume)
  - Lopéz, Francisco, Sculptor ("OCHOA"), 1993 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    (business card; letter to TYF from Lopéz, 03/17/1993, with information about the exhibit "Borderless Art" Sculpture North and South of the Rio Grande, Gallup Area Arts Council, Gallup, New Mexico)
  - Lopez, Martina, 1991-1995; (clippings) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lopéz, Yolanda (see also: Chicano Expressions), 1978-1984, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    (photographs of works of art; letter to TYF from Lopéz, 03/14/1979; catalogs; TYF's notes on Lopéz; clipping; poem, "Don Juanito"; Rachel Anderson's piece of writing, "A Journal," about Lopéz)
  - Los Angeles, California (see also: Barraza, Santa; Gamboa, Diane; García, Margaret; Los Streescapers; Martinez, Daniel; Valadez, John; Valdez, Patssi), 1983, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    (publication event announcement; catalog, Only L.A.: Contemporary Variations, 27 Los Angeles Artists, Los Angeles Municipal Art Gallery, Los Angeles, California, 1986; exhibition announcements; clippings)
  - Los Four (see also: Almaraz, Carlos; de la Roche, Roberto; Hernandez, Judithe; Luján, Gilbert Sánchez - "Magu"; and Romero, Frank), 1973, 1974, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    (collaborative group consisting of Carlos Almaraz, Gilbert Luján, Roberto de la Roche, and Frank Romano; catalog; list of collective works; press resleases; Gilbert Luján course outline, Cultural Studies 20; clippings; exhibition announcement)
  - Lotería, undated; (game pieces) (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Love and Rockets, Comic Magazine, 1985-1986, 1988; (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
    (books 1 and 2, Fantagraphic Books, Inc., Agoura, California, 1985, 1986; Love & Rockets issue 28, 1988; Greed issue 5, 1988, with feature article, "Love and Rockets Los Bros Hernandez and the Marvel of the Real")
  - Low Rider Magazine (see: Cholos) (Box 16)
  - Lowriders (see also: Cholos), 1972-1984, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    (decals; postcards and photographs of art; photographs; clippings; TYF's notes; flyers; Vajito "Low Rider Lirfestyle Magazine", vol. 1, no. 1, 1981)
  - Lucero, Helen, 1990-1991, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    (letter to TYF from Lucero, 12/17/1990, re. Rockefellar Foundation fellowship, with application letter, proposal and resume)
  - Lucero, Linda, undated; (polaroid photograph) (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Lucero, Michael, 1995; (clipping) (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Lucero, Stephen P., 1979-1983, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    (resume/artist biography; photocopy of letter to Samuel Carabajal, from Msgr. A. Lanzoni, Department Head, Secretariat of State, the Vatican, 09/05/1981; clipping)
  - League of United Chicano Artists (LUCHA), Organization, Austin, Texas, 1978-1990, undated; (see also: Museo del Barrio, Austin, Texas; Rodrigues, Pedro; Box 30) (Box 16, Folder 15)
    (catalog; exhibition announcements; clippings; note to TYF from Juan Pablo, 11/19/1982; flyers; Enlucha newsletter: Summer 1982, Fall 1982; illustrated poem, "Will Not Harm the Ozone" by Angela de Hoyos, illustration by Ramón Vásquez y Sánchez)
  - Luján, Gilbert Sánchez (Magu; see also: Los Four), 1983-1985, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
    (exhibition announcements, one with note to TYF from "Magu"; clipping of article by Luján; illustrated letter to TYF from Lujan, 06/26/2002, and illustrated envelope)
  - Luján, Pedro, Sculptor (see also: Blue Star Art Space), 1977, 1996, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
    (catalogs; resume; exhibition announcement; clipping; typescript and handwritten draft of TYF essay)
  - Macías, Susan, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    (undergradute thesis, "Chicano Artists of the Pacific Northwest"; letter to TYF from Macías, 07/21/1989)
  - El Maizal: The National Chicano/Latino Newspaper of the Arts, Newspaper, San Antonio, Texas. Vol. 1, no. 2, undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Malagamba, Amalia (see also: Cardenas, Gilberto), 1994 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    (letter to TYF from Malagamba, 07/16/1994)
  - Maldonado, Alex, Painter, 1901-1989, undated, 1974-1983 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    (1981 calendar with photograph of Maldonado's work; clippings; exhibition announcement; artist bio; copies of letters to Maldonado - not from TYF - 07/21/1976, 10/08/1975, 11/22/1976; photograph of work of art)
  - Maldonado, Jeff Abbey, circa 2000; (catalog) (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Manteca (see also: Galería de la Raza/Studio 24 - (Re)Generation Project), 1996-1997 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    (publication of the (Re)Generation Project, Galería de la Raza/Studio 24. Vol. 1, no. 1, 1986; 1987 issue)
  - Manuelita's, Art Gallery, San Francisco, California, 1989; (exhibition announcements) (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Manzanares, Rick, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    (letters to TYF from Mazanares, 08/14/1990, 11/07/1990; script for a Dios de los Muertos performance)
  - Maradiaga, Ralph, 1981-1985 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    (TYF's notes on Maradiaga; resume; letter to René [associate of Maradiaga], from TYF, 07/22/1985 photocopy, expressing condolences at Maradiaga's death; exhibition and memorial announcements)
  - Mariscal, Joe, 1977, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    (resume; Joe Mariscal: The Inmate Series curatorial statement, Terri Cohn, de Saisset Museum, Santa Clara University; biographical sketch)
  - Martínez, César Augusto (see also: Lomas Garza, Carmen), 1980-1999 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    (exhibition announcements; The Canadian Club Hispanic Art Tour call for entries, Martínez painting featured; letter to TYF from Martínez, 04/12/1985; resume; letter to TYF from Lynn Goode, 10/19/1992, re. TYF's purchase of a Martínez piece; ArtPace International Artist-In-Residence Program brochure, 1997; catalog; clippings)
  - Martínez, Daniel, 1993-1999, undated; (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 29-30)
    (clippings; catalogs; pencils; exhibition announcements; book by Martínez, The Things You See When You Don't Have a Grenade, Smart Art Press, Santa Monica, California, 1996; Camerawork: A Journal of Photographic Arts, vol. 29, no. 2 Fall/Winter 2000)
  - Martínez, Manuel, Painter, 1947-, undated, 1970-1977 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    (artist biography; TYF's notes on Martínez - 1/2 p.; clippings)
  - Martínez, Olga, undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
    (essay by Martínez)
  - Martínez, Pablo (Paul), 1992-1995, undated (Box 16, Folder 33)
    (postcards to TYF from Martínez, 03/11/1992, 03/25/1992, 07/15/1992, 12/11/1992, 06/05/1992, 06/19/19920, 6/12/1992, 02/24/1992, 08/09/1985, 06/07/1995, 08/28/1994, 09/16/1994, 09/16/[?], 05/20/1992, 01/24/1994, 05/14/1993, 03/31/1993, 05/25/1993; note to TYF from Martínez, 11/12/1993; letters to TYF from Martínez, 08/27/1992[?], 02/26/1992, 01/03/1994, 12/11/1992, 08/03/1992, 01/21/1993; clippings)
  - Martínez, Ramiro, 1987; (clipping) (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Martínez, Santos, undated (Box 16, Folder 35)
    (photocopy of document listing pieces of art, with commentary)
  - Martínez, Sue, undated; (resume) (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Martínez, Thomas M. (see: Lecture Notes) (Box 16)
  - Martínez, Xavier, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    (catalog, Xavier Martinez (1869-1943) by Geoerge W. Neubert, The Oakland Museum Art Special Gallery, Oakland, California, 1974)
  - Mechicano Art Center, Los Angeles, California, 1970-1977, undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
    (organization history; address list; clippings; 1 page TYF's notes on the center)
  - Meeting of Historians and Critics of Chicano Art, San Antonio, Texas (see also: Quirarte, Jacinto), 1980 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    (appendices A-E: sample syllabus, reading list, slide list and bibliography for a semester course of Chicano art history and appreciation)
  - Méndez, Nina (see: Chicano Cultural Conference) (Box 16)
  - Mendez, Consuelo, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    (clipping of article by Shifra Goldman; photocopy of catalog, with note to Shifra [Goldman] from Méndez)
  - Mendoza, John, 1969-1970; (clippings) (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Mesa-Bains, Amalia (see also: Altars; Cinco de Mayo; MoCHA), 1987-2003, undated; (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 42-43)
    (catalogs; clippings; postcards to TYF from Mesa-Bains, undated; typescript of speech by Mesa-Bains given at the Dialogue of the Americas Museum of Anthropology, 1982; exhibition announcements; writings by Mesa-Bains; letters to TYF from Mesa-Bains, undated; handwritten draft of essay sent to TYF; resume; note to TYF and Dudley from Mesa-Bains, 04/28/2000; invitation; typescript of "An Affecting Presence: Chicano Altars and Altarmakers" by TYF; draft of "Galaza Stanford lecture" given by Mesa-Bains, 1995; photograph, Edward Diaz, director of Cultural Affairs, City of San Antonio, Amalia Mesa-Bains, TYF; letter to TYF from Mesa-Bains, undated, with aluminum heart)
  - Meta Studio I, circa 1981; (see Box 31) (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Metamorfosis, Magazine, Centro de Estudios Chicanos, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington (see also: Arreguín, Alfredo; Burciaga, José Antonio; Goldman, Shifra; Gamboa, Harry Jr.; Herrara, Juan Felipe; Montoya, José; Montoya, Malaquias; Rodriguez, Patricia; Rodriguez, Pedro; Sanchez, Ruben), 1977-1985 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    (1977 [vol. 1, no. 1]; vol. 1, no. 2, 1978; vol. 2, nos. 1-2, 1979; vol. 3, no. 1, 1980; vol. 3, no. 2/vol. 4, no. 1, 1980/1981; vol. 5, no. 2/vol. 6, no. 1, 1984/1985)
  - Mexic-Arte, 1986-1993; (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    (multi-cultural arts organization/museum, Austin, Texas; symposium program; invitation; membership brochures/forms; 1 page TYF's notes, "Funding Landscapes"; catalog; clippings; Mexic-Arte Museum information packet, with exhibition announcement, brochure; press release, survey, mission statements, Latino Museum Professionals Network project information, TYF's notes (1 p.); IUP News Report Winter 1992-93; clippings)
  - Mexican Art (Box 17)
    - General, 1972-1996; (see also: Barrio, Raymond) (Box 17, Folder 3)
      (clippings; TYF's notes on Mexican art and artists, periods, genres, and a sketch of Chipingo; lecture announcement; photocopy of slides; catalog; book by Raymond Barrio, Mexico's Art and Chicano Artists, Ventura Press, Sunnyvale, California, 1975)
    - Key Periods and Monuments, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      (bibliographies; clippings; typed outline for "Painted Walls of Mexico")
    - Mexico, 1962-1976 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      (reprints and photocopies of articles by Alan W. Barnett and George E. Fay; catalog)
  - The Mexican Cultural Heritage Gardens and Plaza Project, 1995-1998 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    (project of the Mexican Heritage Corporation, San José, California. Project document, "Case for support; clippings; information packet with mission statement, brochure, clippings, program information)
  - Mexican-American Self-Help Group (MASH; see: Paño Arte) (Box 17)
  - Mexican Culture, 1984; (clipping) (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum, Chicago, Illinois, 1985-2005; (7 folders; see also: Box 30) (Box 17, Folder 8-14)
    (catalogs; exhibition and event announcements; invitations; information about the organization, including history of the center and the museum, mission statement; clippings; letters to TYF re. his loan of art to the museum, 1987; letter to TYF from Rene Arceo Frutos, 08/10/1990, re TYF's consent to write an essay for the 1990 Dia De Los Muertos catalog; coloring book; Del Corazon Mexican Performing Arts Festival information packet including calendar of events, stickers, booklet, performer/artist cards, clippings; Sor Juana Festival information packets, with announcements, calendars of events, clippings, booklets; press releases; gala invitations; Mexicanidad information packet with clippings, postcard, invitation)
  - Mexican Heritage Project, Arizona Historical Society, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    (memo to Steve Harvath, from Tom Peterson, 11/05/1991, re. Draft Responsibilities of the AHS Staff Coordinator for the Mexican Heritage Project)
  - Mexican Museum, San Francisco, California (Box 17)
    - Catalogs (see also: Buitrón, Robert; Gamboa, Harry Jr.; Gandert, Miguel; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Noriega, Chon; Vargas, Kathy), 1981-1996; (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 16-17)
      (catalogs: The Mexican Museum Catalog of Selections from Its Collection With Introductions to Mexican and Mexican American Art, 1981; The Mexican Museum, 1983, with essay on Alfredo Arreguín by TYF; Lo Del Corazón: Heartbeat of a Culture, 1986, with text by Amalia Mesa-Bains and TYF; TYF's notes on Lo Del Corazí; From the West: Chicano Narrative Photography, 1996; Ceremony of Spirit, 1993; The Chicano Codices: Encountering Art of the Americas, 1992; Chicano Progeny: Investigative Agents, Executive Council, and Other Representatives from the Sovereign State of Aztlán., 1995; "Press Conference for design Architect" binder, 1995)
    - General (see also: Dia de los Muertos; García, Rupert; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Murals; Rios, Richard and Graciela; Rodriguez, Pedro), 1972-2005, undated; (3 folders) (Box 17, Folder 18-20)
      (exhibition announcements; clippings; museum information sheets; "mural walk to the Mexican Museum" handout; The Mexico Today Symposium booklet; invitations; administrative paperwork, including meeting minutes, correspondence, by-laws, memos, Fort Mason lease information, director's reports, and budgetary documents; press releases; museum membership cards; TYF's notes on Chicano art in the Bay area; membership forms and brochures; photocopy of letter to Jesse Aguirre, Chairman of the Board, The Mexican Museum, from TYF, 06/09/1981; Day of the Dead flyers; resumes; calendars of events; planning documents for the California Chicano Murals project; education programs booklet; newsletter: vol. 1, nos. 1-3, March, June, Dec., 1976; vol. 2, nos. 1 & 2 April, November 1977; vol. 3, nos. 1 & 2, Summer, Dec. 1978; vol. 4, nos. 1 & 2 July, October)
  - Mexican Museum, continued (Box 18)
    - General, continued, (18 folders; 2 folders for 1983; see also: Acosta-Colñn, Marie; Arreguín, Alfredo; Gronk; INTAR; Lomas-Garza, Carmen; Montoya, José; Valdez, Patssi; Box 30) (Box 18, Folder 1-18)
      (see above, and: letter to TYF from Gloria Jaramillo, Curator of Collections, 04/27/1983, re. TYF's purchase of a ceramic by Richard and Graciela [Rios] and sales receipt; photocopy of letter to "Compañeros", from TYF, 09/30/1983; photocopy of letter to Mariano and Linda, from TYF, 09/30/1983; TYF's notes on issues concering the museum's Board of Directors; "Annotated Bibliography of Mexican Folk Art" by Beverly Herzog and Dr. Joyce Bishop, 1985; letter to TYF from the museum, re. a lecture TYF would give for the "From Inside Out..." exhibition; administrative planning documents for "From Inside Out..." and "Lo Del Corazó", including artists' applications and booklet of artists' statements for "Lo Del Corazó"; "Bibliography for the Exhibit 'Folk Art of Michcacan'" by Susan Warren-Kunkler; "Assessment of the Mexican Museum, Museum Assessment Program, American Association of Museums"; "Communal Land Paintings From Central Mexico: An Overview" by Marion Oettinger, Jr., Curator of Folk Art and Latin American Art, San Antonio Museum Association; "But Is It Folk? Defining the Field" by Joyce M. Bishop, presented at "From the Inside Out..."; typescript of essay by Jim Griffith, no title; "Notes Toward An Interpretive History of California-Mexican Music" by Manuel Peña; "From the Inside Out..." symposium program; postcard to TYF from Aurelio and Cecilia Barrera, 10/27/1987; letter to TYF from David de la Torre, Director, The Mexican Museum, 02/08/1988, re. dinner to honor TYF; bound volume, From the Inside Out... Proceedings from the conference, ed. Karana Hattersley-Drayton, Joyce Bishop, TYF, 1989; NEH grant application materials; Christmas card to TYF from Marie Acosta-Colón; slides; letter to José Montoya, from Peter Rodriguez, 11/30/1990, (cc: TYF; photocopy; grant proposals; "The Mexican Museum Long Range Work Plan," CAC Multicultural Advancement Program, circa 1993; photocopy of letter to TYF from Jonathan [Yorba], 06/05/1996; note to Jonathan [Yorba] from TYF, 06/17/1996; artist biographies by TYF, undated: Daniel Salazar and José Alfredo Mendoza Arreguín; newsletter: vol. 7 Spring 1982; vol. 8 (Summer 1983); Winter and Spring 1988; Spring/Summer 1990; Fall/Winter 1990; Fall 1991; Winter/Spring 1992; Spring/Summer 1992; Fall 1992; Winter/Spring 1993; Fall 1993; Winter 1997; Fall 1998; Spring - Fall 1999; Winter 2000 - Summer 2001)
    - Rufino Tamayo Exhibition, 1983; (invitation; administrative materials; clippings) (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Mexican Soldaderas and Workers During the Revolution, Exhibition, University of California at Santa Barbara, 1979; (catalog) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Mexico, circa 1980-1983 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    (clippings; blank postcards; Bi-Cultural Arts Program, US-Mexico, leaflet)